I realize that you probably wouldn't know
what to say to this,
but I want you to hear it.
I guess I should start three years ago.
Back when we still could've
changed something.
Captain!
No word from the advance party.
It's been two hours.
Hmm.
Then have teams two and three
prepare to land as well.
Yes, sir!
These damned island devils managed to
defeat our Warrior unit.
We need to find out
what they're doing now
and relay it back to Marley.
Grab onto something!
It's... It's a devil!
Hello, ladies and gentlemen of Marley!
Welcome to Paradis Island!
Nice to meet'cha. I'm Hange!
And it's an honor to welcome
guests who've sailed from
oh-so-far across the sea to come here!
The trip must've left you exhausted,
so why not join us for some tea?
Oh! I almost forgot.
If you were curious about
this guest of ours,
he arrived just before you
and we're already
getting along splendidly!
Isn't that right? Tell them,
Nicolo!
Please, Captain!
Forget about me and gun these
devils down while you can!
Huh? What are you saying?
Captain!
He's saying that he doesn't wanna be
part of your shitty skit.
Nicolo.
Know this, you wretched devils!
Marley doesn't negotiate
with filthy-bloods like you!
And we're certainly not
gonna sit down with you
and drink the pig piss you call tea!
Huh?! Aw. Ya sure about that?
Maybe you should be more polite.
Unless you wanna piss off
the Titan looming behind you.
Marley will never bend
to the power of devils!
This is all she has to say to you!
Huh?
Put your hands up, Yelena!
Lay down your weapons.
What are you...?
Do as she says.
Hange. I'd like to
accept your invitation.
Let's have some tea.
How I've longed to meet you, Eren.
That big lady shot and killed her captain
without a second thought.
What do you think she's hoping to do?
Can't say, but even if she's on our side,
we obviously can't trust her.
No napping, Sasha.
Yeah, but this is still
an incredible chance
for us to gather information.
We're really lucky we found them.
You're right. We've been lucky.
We managed to intercept
that ship by pure chance.
If Marley comes to this island
in force, we're finished.
We've gotta do something.
Ohh? Ohh!
Oh, I see now!
So that's why your guns
can shoot so many bullets!
Back in Marley, those weapons
are standard-issue.
The Marleyan army is
comprised of 50 divisions,
each made up of 20,000 troops.
That comes out to a million
soldiers in total.
Then there's the Marleyan navy.
It's divided into three fleets,
with 21 battleships each.
Marley's been developing
new weapons, too.
They're making strides in
the field of aerial warfare.
Aerial?
Tch. Keep it together or
they'll think we're weak.
I know that!
In other words,
they're making flying ships,
which can circumvent walls
by attacking from the sky.
Huh?! They'll attack
from the sky?!
Hange.
If Marley truly has the
kind of military capabilities
you just described to us,
why haven't they sent an
invasion force in the past year?
Tell me.
There are two primary reasons.
The first is the Pure Titans
Marley released here.
They pose a serious threat
to a landing force,
even if that force is armed
with the latest weaponry.
They were originally taken
here to keep you Eldians
confined within your walls,
but in more recent times,
they've served as Eldia's
first line of defense.
You don't say.
Well, isn't that funny?
But it'll be morning shortly,
and day is when Titans become active.
Which tells me that if we're still here,
sipping tea in the wilderness
beyond the walls,
you must have killed all the Pure Titans
that were roaming around.
Is my assessment correct?
And what if it is?
You gonna take that intel back to Marley?
Never. It's amazing.
I am in awe.
So what's the second reason?
Marley is occupied.
It's at war with an alliance
of several nations.
It can't be bothered to
deal with Paradis now.
You defeated the Warrior unit:
The pride of Marley.
And in doing so, you stripped Marley of
two of its best weapons:
The Colossal and Female Titans.
Marley is a nation with many enemies.
Once they saw that you'd
left it in a weakened state,
they quickly joined
as one and declared war.
I'm guessing that your group
infiltrated the Marleyan Army
because you have some
sort of grudge against it.
Are you undercover agents
from some of the nations
that Marley's conquered?
Oh? So I'm right!
If you're willing to
go up against Marley,
then you must be working with
some seriously powerful backers.
Sorry to disappoint,
but we're not agents
or anything of the sort.
We were utterly powerless.
Marley took our homes and
conscripted us into its army.
The hope that we could
eventually strike back
faded more every day.
That is, until we met him.
People feared that Titan the world over.
They called him a devil.
But to me, he looked like
something else entirely.
A god.
One that gave hope to the powerless.
Our mutiny was carried out
at the express command of Zeke Jaeger.
We're the Anti-Marleyan Volunteers.
And our goal is to
free the Eldian people.
So, that concludes
Zeke Jaeger's requests.
He claims that he can
save the Eldian people,
who's existence is currently under th...
Absurd!
We shouldn't even be listening to this!
We're talking about the Beast Titan here!
He turned the people
of Ragako into Titans
and spread terror within the walls!
He hunted the Scouts to near-extinction!
Now he has the gall to
come to us with requests?
Zeke Jaeger's one and only goal is to
steal the Founding Titan
from this island.
He failed to by force,
so now he's trying to
obtain it through diplomatic means.
Yes, he should know
that we'll assume that.
Regardless, I would still like
to hear what else he has to say.
Zeke Jaeger claims to
have an actionable plan
that can solve all our
people's problems at once.
And to carry this plan out,
we would need two key assets:
The Founding Titan, and a Titan
possessing royal blood.
He says that with both,
the world can be saved.
However, he will only reveal
the details of his plan
after his conditions have been met.
He's full of shit!
What kind of feckless idiots
does he take us for?
Eren?
Zeke is telling
the truth. I remember.
The Founder's power has always been
completely impossible for me to use.
The only exception was when I touched
a Titan with royal blood.
I recognize that Titan from a picture.
It had to be my dad's
first wife. Dina Fritz.
Zeke is Dina's son.
He must have figured it out, too.
How to get around the
king's vow renouncing war.
How to activate the only hope
that still remains to us Eldians.
He knows how to wake
the millions of Titans
sleeping in the walls.
How to start The Rumbling,
and crush the world.
Hey. Why did you keep
quiet about this for so long?
'Cause I was concerned
for Historia's safety.
At the time, I wasn't sure,
and I couldn't let her
get turned into a Titan
based on some hunch of mine.
It wasn't a well-thought-out
decision, I see that.
We'll talk about it later.
However, if everything
that you're saying is true,
then Zeke's secret plan holds up.
You trust them? Have you
lost your mind, Hange?
The fact is, we can't risk letting these
Marleyan soldiers roam the island freely.
If we were smart, we'd hang them!
No. That's not an option.
If we want to protect Paradis
from Marley's survey ships,
we need the volunteer's help.
They have something
called a "radio."
This is Survey Ship
One. Requesting immediate aid.
This is Survey Ship One!
Please respond!
We read you.
What's your situation?
Thank goodness!
Our ship ran aground!
We've been waiting so long for help.
We're
coming! In the cove, huh?
Our numbers? Don't worry!
We're sending two survey ships your way.
Hey! You all right?
We're coming to pick you up!
It's the Colossal Titan!
How?!
Hey! It's the enemy!
Hurry! Jump off!
Swim for the coast!
Abandon ship!
Welcome to our defiled island
of filth-blooded devils.
You're gonna love it here.
Long as you like drinking pig piss.
Feel free to turn us down,
but if you don't wanna come ashore,
you'll need to swim back home.
It was fun back then.
We knew that as Eldians,
we were feared and hated
by the rest of the world.
By people on the other side of the sea
whose faces we had never even seen.
But not everyone across
the sea was an enemy.
That fact gave us comfort.
And we finally got to learn
about the outside world
in all its complexities and mysteries.
Oh, by the way.
Why is your skin so dark, Onyonkopon?
Because our creator thought that
things would be more interesting
if the world were occupied
by many kinds of people.
I'd say that applies to you
Subjects of Ymir as well.
We exist because we were wanted.
Wait, we were created? By who?
By the one who gave power
to your Founder Ymir.
It was God.
Well, that's what some people believe.
We're all free to think
as we like, right?
What the hell is this food?
Is it even edible?
Smells pretty fishy.
Have you never had seafood before?
Nicolo's a master when it
comes to Marleyan cuisine.
Dumb jerks. If you don't like
how it looks, then don't eat it.
Like I care what Eldians think...
It's so good!
Slow down!
No fair, Sasha!
You're a genius.
This is the best food I've ever eaten!
Hey. Stop eating like
some kind of pig!
I've never tasted anything like this!
There's plenty, so take your time.
We should be finished
building the port soon.
Progress has been fast
since those Marleyan engineers
decided to help out.
I'm kind of surprised they agreed to.
It took time.
At first, we were too suspicious
to cooperate at anything.
But as we gradually set aside the labels
we have for one another,
and work to see each other as people,
we can reach an understanding.
Armin. Have you seen any
of Bertholdt's memories?
Uh... yeah, but I didn't notice
anything that seemed helpful.
We're short on time.
Zeke has less than three years to live.
Yeah, but about that.
Do you really think it's okay for us
to just go along with Yelena's plan?
What's the problem?
I just wonder if we really have to
threaten the world with the Rumbling
to protect the Eldian people.
We'd be forcing everyone
to live in fear of us.
Acting like the devils they think we are.
Before it comes to that,
why don't we just talk to them?
If we fix the world's
misconceptions about us,
threats won't be needed.
Come again? What
misconceptions do they have?
You know. How they think
we're scary monsters.
They think that because we can transform
into man-eating Titans.
That's no "misconception."
But still. There are
some Marleyans who like us.
How many?
Most of the Marleyans we caught
are still glaring at us
from their prison cells.
That's true for now,
but given enough time.
Yeah. We just need time.
That's right, and to
buy ourselves that time,
we need to show the world our strength.
I still don't know
that we made the right choice back then.
I can't help but wonder if there was
some other path we could've
taken, if we'd just seen it.
I used to think
that I understood Eren
better than anyone.
Even Mikasa.
But... I don't know anymore.
Hey! Aren't you a Marleyan?
What the hell are you doing?
This graveyard is full of
people your kind killed!
You have no right...
Hey, stop!
Let us take care of this guy!
I'm sorry, but please.
Marleyans can go to hell.
Hey, Nicolo!
You okay?
No. Why, damn it?
Is it true that Sasha was killed?
So it is. Then why?
What the hell were you guys doing?
Shot by a kid who snuck onto the airship?
It's too ridiculous to be true.
It wasn't an ordinary kid.
The girl had been trained.
Sounds like a Warrior candidate.
Should've kept my
guard up. I'm sorry.
Why apologize to me?
All I did was cook her a meal or two.
Thank you.
Thank you for every tasty meal
you made for her, Nicolo.
How are you taking it, Conny?
Sasha and I were like twins.
So it feels like half of me is just gone.
It's her family.
Y'all were friends
with my daughter, Sasha?
Uh. Pardon.
I'm just a captive Marleyan,
but I have permission to work as a chef.
Your daughter loved my cooking
more than anyone else ever will, I think.
So um, if you ever want to,
please come and let me
cook you something.
This would be on the house, right?
Yeah.
How interesting.
They're calling it a victory?
Ignorance is scary,
but delusion's even worse.
I'm going to kill you and
ship your corpse back to Marley,
with a note about your little plot.
Should spell the end
for your grandparents.
That said, if this secret plan
of yours isn't bullshit,
I can wait and chop you up
once it's finished.
I don't care much either way.
Well, I appreciate your
willingness to accommodate.
But hey. I do get to
meet Eren soon, don't I?
There's no need to rush.
We've prepared a nice little
place for you to stay here.
A beautiful hotel that you can relax at.
So, could I ask you to stop glaring?
This is all the Titan
transformation serum
we were able to steal from Marley.
Sorry, but it's hard to reproduce.
It's fine. For our
purposes, this should be plenty.
I just wish that we were in a position
to return your kindness.
We owe you so much already.
You turned our ignorance into
hope and got nothing in return.
For us to doubt the people who saved us,
we truly are no better than devils.
It is my opinion that
we've proven ourselves
to be your loyal friends
over these past three years.
This is a shame.
The weapons that we offered you as gifts
were intended to bring freedom
to the Eldian people.
I know that this is a selfish request,
but would you please overlook
our weakness for a time?
We're going to great lengths
to keep Zeke on a tight leash.
It's fine, Commander.
I understand.
The day will soon come when we
sit at the same table once again.
This is my hotel?
What better lodging could there be?
It's a giant forest.
Difficult to move through
and devoid of boulders.
Looks like a fun spot
for using ODM gear, too.
Hey. Quick question.
This natural wonder.
Would you mind letting me
show it to Gabi and Falco?
Tch. Whether they get to see the
sights or not depends on you.
I'll kill you, Eren Jaeger.
Eren was ready to do it alone.
Whether we helped him or abandoned him.
The outcome would've
been awful either way.
But now, we've killed
a huge number of people.
Sailors. Soldiers. Civilians.
The devastation we spread
was indiscriminate.
Still, if we had left that port intact,
then Marley would've launched
an immediate counterattack
against our island.
We've abandoned all hope for peace,
but we didn't have a choice.
Any more than the three of you did.
Right, Annie?
Say something. Please.
Kill or be killed.
Fight for your life.
The only way to live is to fight.
So fight. Just fight.
Without any allies on the outside,
they must kill their
enemies in order to live.
But is that the right choice to make?
There isn't a soul who knows.
Next episode:
"A Sound Argument."